妈妈  杰斯罗在吃我的小内裤
Mom! Jethro's eating my underwear!
这里  猪猪  猪猪  杰斯罗
Here, piggy, piggy, piggy. Jethro.
妈  她发飙前没有一点儿迹象
Mom, before she starts, there isn't a shred of evidence
-也不说任何理由  -吉莉安  你儿子有病
- to support her allegations. - Gillian, your son is a psycho.
-他在我的吹风机上动手脚  -猜想不错啊  但是你不能证明
- He booby-trapped my hair dryer. - Nice hypothesis, but you can't prove it.
-的确不能  但是我能揍你  -妈  妈  该把她送到医院去
- Yeah, but I can hurt you. - Mom! Mom! She needs to be medicated.
-这里来  杰斯罗  -这里
- Come on, Jethro. - Come here.
我讨厌这家  这里来
I hate this family. Come here.
杰斯罗  你耽搁我们太多时间了
Jethro, you're getting a time out.
快点  背包
Come on, guys. Backpack.
-怎么  这是潮流  -这不合适  去换牛仔裤
- What? It's in style. - It's inappropriate. Go put on some jeans.
还有吐掉口香糖
And spit out the gum.
今天想穿什么颜色呢
So, what color do you want to wear today?
-红  蓝  紫
Red? Blue? Purple?
-粉色  妈咪  粉色
Pink, Momma, pink.
-法瑞恩  -怎么  不是你说的穿牛仔吗
- Farren. - What? You said jeans.
我是说合适你的衣服
I meant in your size.
快点  大家快点  我们不想迟到的
Come on, guys. Come on. We don't want to be late. There you go.
快点  甜心
Come on, sweetie.
-不  -出去
- No! - Get out!
不许打架
No fighting.
让我来
Allow me.
-我们还会一起吃饭吗  -我会去的
- Are we still on for dinner? - I'll be there.
有人在看
We have an audience.
- 呀  我想吐了  -他是个失败者
- Yuck. I'm going to vomit. - He is such a loser.
我喜欢鲍勃  他人很好
I like Bob. He's nice.
他是个无趣的卖笔的 每天都过一样的生活
He's a boring pen importer. He does the same routine every day.
-他就像个机器人  -因为他就是个机器人
- He's like a robot. - That's 'cause he is a robot.
来自未来的电子人  来毁灭人类的  从我们开始
A cyborg, sent from the future, to destroy humanity. Starting with us.
哇  三个月了  纪念日快乐
Well, it's been three months. Happy anniversary.
怎么了
What is it?
我必须告诉你我工作的事
I have to tell you about my job.
可能会吓到你
This might shock you,
但在关系进一步发展之前  你应该知道知道所有事情
but you should know everything before this relationship goes further.
-别  鲍勃  -怎么
- Don't, Bob. - What?
跟你在一起我很快乐
I'm very happy when I'm with you.
没有人像你一样可以让我开心地笑
No one has ever made me laugh like you do,
如果我是孤身一人  相信我们会有结果的
and if I were a single woman, I could see a real future for us.
但是现在是一揽子交易
But I'm a package deal.
什么意思
What do you mean?
孩子们是我优先考虑的事  我怎么能忽略他们呢
My kids are my priority and... How can I put this gently?
-他们讨厌我  -是啊
- They hate me. - Yeah.
-我可以让他们喜欢我  -明白吗
- I can make them like me. - See?
你不能让孩子们喜欢你  我的孩子不会  别人的孩子也不会
You can't make kids like you, not mine or anyone's.
我的孩子经历过很多
My kids have been through a lot, and...
在他们接受之前  我不认为我们该进一步发展
I don't think we should take the next step until they warm up to you.
你的幸福不重要吗
Doesn't your happiness count?
不好意思
Excuse me.
对不起  该走了  工作上的急事
Sorry, I gotta go. Emergency at work.
-没墨水了  -严重多了
- No ink? - It's much bigger.
-对不起  真的  -我明天跟你解释一切
Sorry, really. I will explain everything tomorrow.
好  明天见
Okay. I'll see you tomorrow.
-怎么这么久才到  -六分钟
- What took you so long to get here? - Six minutes.
-中途停下要了杯咖啡  -我知道了  你
- You stop for a latte? - I get it. You're...
-那句话怎么说来着  没事找事儿  -差不多
- What's the expression? Chopping my bust. - Close enough.
波尔达克和一些俄国佬  刚刚进了一个提炼厂
Poldark and a couple other Russkys just went in the refinery.
那我猜对了  他又在打歪主意了
Then I was right. He's planning something.
或许只是想免费搞点石油
Maybe they just want to fill up their gas tanks for free.
-不能责怪他们  -是啊  那个家伙太狡猾了
- I couldn't blame them. - No, that man's so crooked,
他若吃了钉子  能拉出螺丝
he could eat nails and poop corkscrews.
全世界就你最了解波尔达克
You're the world's foremost authority on Poldark.
你觉得他想干嘛
What do you think he's up to?
如果他的任务是破坏世界石油储备
If his mission is to sabotage the world's oil reserves,
他干嘛对像这样不值钱的精炼厂感兴趣
why would he care about some two-bit refinery like this one?
我保证给你机会亲自问他
I'll make sure you get a chance to ask him.
你丫怎么进去啊  坐火箭筒喷进去
How the heck are you going to get in there? A jet pack?
小菜一碟
It's in the shop.
等我信号
Wait for my signal.
好啊
Yuri.
-这是什么  -C4炸药
- What's this? - C-4.
弄完之后  把这地方炸掉
When we are done here, I want you to blow this place to smithereens.
快点  我可没时间跟你们耗  没有加班费
Hurry up. I don't have all day. There is no overtime here.
鲍勃·贺
Bob Ho.
我喜欢聊天  可这会儿没时间陪你
I would love to chat, but I gotta go.
-上面  快  快  -快
- Up there. Go, go, go, go. - Move it.
-快  -站住  都不许动
- Move. - Hold it. Stay where you are.
有趣啊  很好的有氧锻炼
That was fun. A good aerobic workout.
有机会真该再来一次
We should do this again sometime.
好了  波尔达克  走
Okay, Poldark, let's go.
你被逮捕了
We have suspect in custody.
伙计  你看到波尔达克的表情了吗
Did you see the look on Poldark's face, man?
干得好  鲍勃  难以置信
Brilliant work, Bob. Unbelievable.
我实在不想让你回去  你可是我最好的干将
I really hate to see you go home. You're the best agent I've ever had.
嘿  照顾下我的情绪好不好
Hey, you know I'm standing right here.
或许我该向你们国家申请多留你一段时间
Maybe I can get your government to loan you to me just a little bit longer.
别  这是我最后一桩任务  我退休了
No. This was my last assignment. I'm retiring.
-别告诉我是为了吉莉安  -我想过平凡的生活  想要结婚
- Don't tell me because of Gillian. - I want a normal life. I want to get married.
噢  伙计  别结婚啊
Oh, heck, man. Don't get married.
用不了几年你就会后悔
Just find some woman that you're going to hate in five years
到时候还要把房子留给人家
and give her your house.
这表送你了  留个纪念吧  中央情报局给你的
Keep the watch. A memento, compliments of the CIA.
吉莉安是住在你房子旁边的那女人吗
So, Gillian? Is that the woman that lives next door to your cover house?
-是啊  他们的关系可不一般啊  -我绝对不会为了一个女的放弃生活
- Yeah, they've been stepping out. - I could never give up this life for a woman.
伙计  我们是特工啊
We're spies, man.
每个男孩都想当特工  这才是生活
Every little boy wants to be a spy. It's the life.
很多时候你要独自坐在这样的小房子里
All the hours you spend sitting alone in a little room like this,
在盯梢货车后面吃冷掉的外带
eating cold take-out food in the back of a surveillance van,
随时都可能被击毙
getting shot at all the time,
学着一边坐车一边用个瓶子上小号
learning how to pee in a bottle in a moving vehicle.
-你的选择是正确的  -唯一的问题是  她的孩子讨厌我
- You're doing the right thing. - Only problem is that her kids hate me.
你真是条汉子
You the man.
真的会很想你  鲍勃  祝你跟那些孩子能合得来
Really gonna miss you, Ho. Good luck with those kids.
大反派我都搞定了  三个孩子能有多大能耐
I've brought down dictators. How tough can three kids be?
-下来  林戈  下来  -这里  猫咪  猫咪
- Come on, Ringo, come on. - Here, kitty, kitty, kitty.
-林戈  -别担心  下来  下来
- Ringo! - Don't worry. Come on. Come on.
-下来  这里  -下来  林戈
- Come on. Right here. - Come on, Ringo.
-下来  林戈  -林戈
- Come on, Ringo. - Ringo.
嗨  孩子们
Hi, kids.
昨天丢下你一个人  很对不起
I'm sorry about running out last night.
-没关系  工作嘛  -不  这很不礼貌
- It's all right. It's your job. - No, it was rude.
我保证这样的事情不会再发生
I promise it will never happen again.
妈妈  林戈怎么办
Mom, what about Ringo?
甜心  我们什么都试过了  他想下来的时候会下来的
We've tried everything, sweetheart. He'll come down when he's ready.
想看我最近在忙什么吗
You want to see what I've been working on?
当然
Sure.
林戈林戈  下来  猫咪  我离你不远啊
Ringo, Ringo! Come on, kitty. It's not that far.
下来下来下来  林戈
Please, please, please, Ringo.
给你
There you go.
-你觉得怎样  -这个
- So, what do you think? - Well...
还没完成
It's a work-in-progress.
很可惜  今天没有一点时间来做这个东西
Sadly, I didn't have any time to work on it today.
猫上屋顶了啊  信号接收器又坏了啊
Cat was on the roof, satellite's broken again.
为了找个修理工  我花了两个小时
I spent two hours on hold trying to get a repairman out here,
而且昨晚的事还老在我脑子里面晃
and I can't stop thinking about last night.
那  我们可以吗
So, are we okay?
我明白
I understand.
如果我娶你  就要接受三个孩子
If a man marries you, he marries all four of you.
还有一只猪  一只猫和一只乌龟
Don't forget the pig, the cat and the turtle.
那你是真的喜欢这画吗
So, do you really like it?
吓到我了
It frightens me.
有的时候我觉得  我找到世界上最诚实的人了
Sometimes I think I found the last honest man left in the world.
给你们带曲奇了
I brought you all cookies.
-这是  -真的吗  你要嫁给鲍勃
- Yes? - Is it true? You're going to marry Bob?
-干嘛  哦  冷静  -你不能这样做  吉莉安
- What? Whoa! Calm down. - You can't do this, Gillian.
你  看起来  比他好太多了
You're, like, so far above him.
她意思是他很无趣  土包子一个
What she means is he's boring. He's a geek.
他是个好男人  对我非常好
He's a very nice man who treats me very well.
-一个卖钢笔的  -还是个电子人
- He's a pen importer. - He's a cyborg.
你们没有我了解他
You all don't know him like I do.
他对世界  对我的艺术都充满热情
He's very passionate about the world and about my art.
喜欢谈论历史  科学和政治
He likes to talk about history, science and politics.
我明白了  这就是你说的不无聊
I see what you mean about him not being boring.
你们认为的无聊  在我看来是可靠
What you all call boring, I call dependable.
这一次  我喜欢每天都按时工作的人
For once, I'd like a man who goes to work every day at the same time,
每晚都回家的人
and who comes home every single night.
一个不撒谎  不骗人  不会像某人一样抛弃家人的
A man who doesn't lie, or cheat, or leave his family the first time some...
我的幸福也重要
My happiness counts, too.
我讨厌大人有感情
I hate it when old people have feelings.
我们要整死鲍勃
We gotta deep-six Bob.
-怎么了  -有人在市郊撞了波尔达克的拘禁车
- What's the story here? - They hit Poldark's prison transport caravan
告诉我他没有逃走
- at the edge of town. - Tell me he didn't get away.
他消失得就像戒酒聚会上的朗姆酒蛋糕
He's as gone as rum cake at an AA meeting.
我觉得整件事都是精心策划的
I'm telling you, this whole thing was a setup.
有人知道他要来
They knew he was coming.
你是说情报局里有内奸
Are you saying there's a mole in the agency?
我什么都没有说啊  除了他逃走了
I'm not saying anything except he got away.
欢迎回来
Welcome back.
塔蒂安娜  你没办法想象  那个地方有多糟糕
Tatiana, you can't imagine what it's like in there.
让人抑郁的黑暗  无聊透顶  度日如年
The oppressive darkness and the torture of empty days stretching for years.
-牢房是地狱  -你在里面才呆四个小时
- Prison is hell. - You were in there for four hours.
不提不开心的事了
Enough tearful reunion.
我要一批新的方程式  尽快
I need a new batch of the formula as soon as possible.
两天内进行新的测试
We'll run another test in two days.
我的衣服该换了  要新潮点儿的
I need a change of clothes. Something current and fashionable.
我还要一些吃的  不跟玩具一起上的那种
And something to eat that does not come with a toy.
甜心  赶快下楼刻南瓜了
Honey, we're getting ready to carve pumpkins downstairs.
-一起来吧  -那是一定的
- You want to join us? - Absolutely!
因为我是个失败者  没有自己的生活
'Cause I'm a loser and I have no life.
我有没有说过我们要烤南瓜子吃
Did I mention we're going to toast the pumpkin seeds?
来吧  我们家少了你可不行
Come on. I want you to join the family.
我想有隐私
And I want some privacy.
-别对我放肆无礼  -我想怎么说话怎么说话
- Don't get fresh with me. - I'll use whatever tone of voice
-我想对你放肆  -法瑞恩  我要你下楼
- I want to use with you. - Farren, I want you downstairs...
不  我不下去  出去
No, I'm not going to come downstairs right now. Get out.
法瑞恩  这是我的房子  你得听我的
Farren, this is my house. You will listen to me.
我又不归你管  出去  我说了  出去  吉莉安  出去
You don't own me. Get out. I said, get out, Gillian. Get out!
五分钟  下楼
Downstairs in five minutes.
我讨厌这房子  我讨厌这个家  出去
I hate this house. I hate this family. Get out!
没有  她听不到我说话  我在屋顶上
No, she won't hear me. I'm on the roof.
在这个疯人院里  屋顶该是我唯一有隐私的地方了
It's like the only place I can get any privacy in this loony bin.
我绝对不可以让吉莉安跟那个家伙结婚
I can't let Gillian marry this guy.
不  不是  我的意思是  他的确是个男的
No, it's not that. I mean, you're right, he is a total drone,
但不是这个问题
but that's not the issue.
我爸爸要是回来了怎么办
What's going to happen when my dad comes back?
他不会只是把我丢在这里  他会回来的
He won't just leave me here alone. He'll be back.
如果她结婚了  会发生什么  我不知道
And if she's married, what happens then? I don't know.
妈妈  伊恩喂杰斯罗熏肉
Mom, lan's feeding Jethro bacon.
-这是不对的  -怎么不对了
- Okay, that's just wrong. - Why is it wrong?
-我是鲍勃  -嘿  跟那些孩子怎么样
- Ho, Bob Ho. - Hey. So, how's it going with those kids?
我要带吉莉安和孩子们去野餐
I'm taking Gillian and the children on a picnic.
迫使他们喜欢我
I'm going to force those kids to like me.
逼他们  你要知道  这跟你用手肘碰耳朵一样不可能
Force them? You know, you might as well try scratching your ear with your elbow.
你猜怎么了  波尔达克逃了
Guess what? Poldark escaped.
-不在其位不谋其政  -是的  我知道  但我们发现了一个文件
- No longer my problem. - Yeah, I know, but we recovered a file.
好像是一个网站的入口
It seems to be an entry portal to a website.
我们没办法破解  我想你可以看一下
We can't crack it. I thought maybe you could take a look at it.
嘿  如果能破  好极了  如果不能  没什么
Hey, if you can figure it out, great. If you can't, no harm, no foul.
那我帮你这个忙吧  发到我邮箱吧
As a favor to you. Send it to my home computer.
已经发了
Already did.
我在想的时候  他们怀疑中情局内部有奸细
While I'm thinking about it, they suspect there may be a mole at the agency.
-他们怀疑我  -不是
- They suspect me? - No.
你可是格雷兹心目中的神兵利器
You know Glaze thinks you're the sharpest barb on the wire.
不知道你在说什么
I have no idea what that means.
嘿  伙计  野餐快乐
Hey, listen, man, have fun on your picnic.
破了密码打给我就是了  拜
Just shoot me back when you check out that file. Thanks.
复杂的密码  看你能有多厉害
Puzzle encryption. Let's see what you've got.
-已经到时间了吗  -不是  我有个坏消息
- Is it noon already? - No. I have bad news.
-我父亲住院了  -真糟糕
- My father is in the hospital. - That's terrible.
他玩老年垒球时摔倒了
He plays senior softball and he slid into third.
-屁股摔得很厉害  -真糟糕
- Now he's having his hip replaced. - That's terrible.
我必须丢下孩子们  飞到丹佛照顾爸爸
I have to leave the kids and fly to Denver to take care of Dad.
-哇  真棒  -你在说什么
- That's great. - What are you talking about?
让我来照看他们
Let me watch the kids.
这样我们就有机会相互了解了
It would give us a chance to get to know each other.
别  鲍勃  你  他们  算了吧
No, Bob. You? Them? I don't know.
我的舅妈要从圣安东尼奥过来  她很擅长带孩子
My aunt's flying in from San Antonio. She's very good with the kids.
-她过去服过兵役  -吉莉安  这样的相处也许正是我们需要的
- She was in the military. - Gillian, this could be just what we need.
你真的觉得你可以承受这样的压力吗
You really think you can handle that kind of pressure?
送他们上学  监督他们学习  还有万圣节
The driving, the schoolwork, and then there's Halloween.
要给他们搞到装扮服装  还有装饰整间屋子
Getting their costumes, finishing decorating the house?
没问题  我最喜欢万圣节了
No problem. Halloween is my favorite.
没什么可担心的  跟我在一起  他们绝对安全
You have nothing to worry about. They will be perfectly safe with me.
我担心的不是他们
It's not them I'm worried about.
-不会吧  -还有别的选择吗
- You can't be serious. - Isn't there any other option?
寄宿学校  少年宫
Foster care? Juvenile hall?
没事的
Okay. You'll be fine.
爱你们
Love you guys.
-我会想你们的  -是啊  这是抛弃我们的很好证明
- I'm going to miss you. - Yeah, as proven by this total abandonment.
你能熬下来的  我会在医院的纪念品店给你们带点东西
You'll survive. I'll buy you something from the hospital gift shop.
-拜  -拜  爱你
- Bye. - Bye. Love you.
-回头见  -拜
- See you later. - Bye.
嘿  这不是很让人激动吗
So, is this exciting, or what?
好吧  我收拾一下东西  就到你们家去  好吗
Well, I'll just pack a few things, and we'll go to your house, okay?
剃头机  我就知道他自己剪头
A Flowbee. I knew he cut his own hair.
DVD碟一点儿都没意思
Nothing telling in his DVD collection.
标准动作片  主流喜剧
Standard action movies, mainstream comedies,
没有科幻的  也没有关于PG-13的东西
no sci-fi, and nothing above PG-13.
嘿  电脑耶  看看有什么
Hey, his computer. Let's check it out.
你就弄吧  上面肯定很脏
Good idea. There's got to be some dirt on there.
老气
Fashion Armageddon.
我没有忘  科尔顿  会看文件的
I haven't forgotten, Colton. I will look at the file.
这个很重要  什么是万圣节
But this is important. What is Halloween?
法瑞恩  你知不知道这是什么
Farren, do you realize what this is?
都让你这样激动起来了  我猜猜  是克林贡词典（《星际迷航》）
It's got you all worked up. Let me guess, a Klingon dictionary?
真不明白这个衰人成天在搞什么
You have me confused with an entirely different class of geek.
斯德哥尔摩GBH
Stockholm GBH.
重伤乐队  斯德哥尔摩演唱会
Grievous Bodily Harm, live in Stockholm.
这是世界上最稀有的非法音乐之一
This is one of the rarest bootleg concerts in the world.
-为什么鲍勃有这个  -谁管他  我要拷下来
- Why does Bob have it? - Who cares? I'm gonna download it.
这是我走向巅峰的开始
This is my ticket to Coolsville.
这就是给我准备的衣服吗
This is what you bring me to wear?
是你自己说要时尚的
You said you wanted current.
我看起来就像是白俄罗斯里的法国王子
I look like the Fresh Prince of Belarus.
派人去给我搞套优雅的
Send someone out to get me something elegant.
这是什么程序
What is this program you found?
我在下载方程式
I went on to download the formula
结果发现网址被第三方侵入
and found the site being accessed by a third party.
如果被是美国或中国下载
If the United States or China has the formula,
他们就可以研究出抗体
they can develop an antibody for it.
正在追踪网络  但是网络被多重加密了
I'm tracing the ISP, but it's heavily encrypted.
要花点时间破解
It will take me a while to track it down.
不管是谁下载了我的方程式  给我找到
Find whoever downloaded my formula.
-找回方程式  -仅仅这样
- Retrieve it. - And?
-杀了他  -对了嘛
- Kill them. - Thank you.
-你要干吗  -我要杀了你
- What's up with you? - I'm gonna kill you.
什么  我要杀了你
What? I'm gonna kill you.
别打我  别打我  她在打我
Don't hurt me! Don't hurt me! She's hurting me!
嘿嘿嘿
Hey, hey, hey.
嘿  住手
Hey, stop!
-怎么了  -她往我房间扔臭弹
- What's going on here? - She threw a stink bomb in my room.
什么  不是我干的
What? That's so not true.
那你说是怎么回事  那就是我自己扔的喽
So what, you're saying I threw a stink bomb in my own room
只是为了陷害你  悲哀  真是悲哀
just to get you in trouble? Sad. So sad.
嘿  嘿  嘿
Hey, hey, hey.
法瑞恩  我对你很失望
Farren, I'm very disappointed in you.
你们现在该睡觉了
You two should be in bed by now.
是这样的  如果我们能够及时完成作业  吉莉安允许我们呆到深夜
Well, if we finish our homework in time, Gillian lets us stay up till midnight.
她也喜欢让我们看《午夜剧场》  这是我们的传统
She also likes us to watch Adult Swim. It's kind of a tradition.
真是想不通
I didn't really think this one through.
诺拉  准备睡觉了
Nora, let's get ready for bed.
我不想睡觉
I don't want to go to bed.
只有妈咪可以给我穿衣服
Only my mommy can dress me.
诺拉
Nora.
我来了
Here I come.
嘿  回来  我要抓到你
Hey! Come back. I'll get you.
回来
Come back!
不要  回来
I got you. No, come back!
诺拉
Nora.
别啊  诺拉
Come on. Nora.
-只有妈咪可以给我穿衣服  -不要啦  诺拉
- Only my mommy can dress me. - Come on, Nora.
只有妈咪可以给我穿衣服
Only my mommy can dress me!
Only mommy can dress me!
你
You.
你妈咪可以做到吗  睡觉
Can your mommy do that? Sleep.
滚出去
Get out!
-喂  -你还活着  好迹象
- Hello? - You're alive. That's a good sign.
-孩子们怎样  -我们都很好  很简单嘛
- How are the kids? - We had a great night. Easy as pie.
真的吗  你是在跟我的孩子在一起吧
Really? You're with my kids, right?
鲍勃  那天晚餐
Bob, the other night at dinner,
你要说你工作的事  我打断了
you were gonna say something about your job, and I cut you off.
现在想告诉我吗
You want to tell me now?
可以等你回来再说
It can wait until you get back.
-我打心眼儿觉得这建议好  -我保证最坏的都过去了
- I really think this was a good idea. - I'm sure the worst is behind us.
马上就好
Just a second.
我来
I got it.
火
Fire!
这下糟了
Big mistake.
一切都没有问题  燕麦好了
Everything will be fine. Oatmeal's ready.
小刺儿头  今天没轮到你
- Shotgun. - It's not your day.
你确定你妈妈允许你穿成这样上学
You sure your mother lets you go to school like that?
要你管
Duh, Bob.
“要你管”
"Duh, Bob."
-拜  -今天要开心啊
- Bye. - Well, you guys have a nice day.
-嗨  -这可真靓
- Hi. - That is so cute.
你今天做什么呢
So what do you do all day?
不做什么  我才四岁
Nothing. I'm four.
-你编的  -绝对是编的
- You're full of it. - Yeah, full of it.
我跟你说  我昨天才下载下来
I'm telling you, I downloaded it yesterday.
是吗  如果是真的  这可炫呆了
Really? 'Cause if you really had, that'd be pretty cool.
-是啊  酷毙了  -我们听听
- Yeah, pretty cool. - Let's hear it then.
你要爆掉我们的耳朵是吧  这只是一堆乱七八糟的静电在闪
You trying to pop our ears? That's nothing but a bunch of static.
-我不懂  -我懂
- I don't get it. - I get it.
你是个可悲的书呆子  骗子  干掉他
You're a pathetic little nerd and a liar. Let's get him.
维基
Wedgie!
放我下来  放我下来  放我下来  放我下来
Put me down! Put me down! Put me down! Put me down!
好啊  这可是你说的
Okay, you asked for it.
不  你们将会受到我和我律师的指控
No! You guys are gonna hear from me and my lawyer.
你们会付出代价  每个人
You'll pay for this, each and every one of you.
跟我说说万圣节吧
So, tell me more about Halloween.
最好的就是它了 我们可以得到糖果
It's the best. You get candy.
每个人都装扮成别人  没有知道你真正是谁
Everyone pretends to be someone else, and nobody knows who you really are.
听起来很熟悉  诺拉
Sounds familiar. Nora...
那么  你想扮什么  科学怪人  僵尸
So, what do you want to be? A Frankenstein? A zombie?
甜心  你想扮公主吗
Sweetie, do you want to be a princess?
是的
Yes.
好  公主
Okay, princess.
这套
Nora?
不是仙女  要公主装  公主装
Not fairy. Princess. Princess.
公主
Princess.
粉色的
Pink.
粉色
-公主装  -太大了
- Princess. - It's too big.
太大了  好吧
Too big? Okay.
诺拉  诺拉
Nora? Nora.
诺拉
Nora.
Nora!
诺拉  对不起  不好意思  不好意思
Nora. I'm sorry. Sorry. Sorry.
诺拉
Nora!
诺拉  以后不要再到处跑了
Nora. Please don't wander off again.
对不起  鲍勃
I'm sorry, Bob.
我们去付钱吧
Let's go pay for your costume.
喂  我是鲍勃
Yo, it's Ho.
在我来之前  让他呆在那里
Just hold him till I get there.
我能否在开始前明确  在美国公立学校的体制下
Can I just say before we begin that only in the current distressed condition
这极其让人忧心的状况里
of the American public school system
被头部朝下栽进垃圾桶中的人是我
could I be deposited headfirst into a garbage can,
难道被迫接受惩罚也应该是我吗
and yet I'm the one who winds up receiving disciplinary action?
你到底是谁
Who exactly are you?
我是他母亲的
I'm his mother's...
-邻居  -邻居
- Neighbor. - Neighbor.
我负责照看他们几天
I'm watching them for a few days.
这不是伊恩第一次惹麻烦了
Well, this is not the first time lan has been in trouble.
他打架  撒谎
He gets in fights. He lies.
嘿  我没撒谎
Hey, I don't lie.
你告诉所有人  你邀请了赛琳娜·戈麦斯来春季舞会
You told everyone you invited Selena Gomez to the spring dance.
她的出场费是一大难题
Her appearance fee was an obstacle.
你说你在花花公子公寓度过了新年前夜
You said you spent New Year's Eve at the Playboy Mansion.
嘿  我看的高清收费电视  这跟真去了没什么两样
Hey, pay-per-view high-def. I felt like I was there.
我警告你  撒谎是很危险的
I'm telling you, lying is a dangerous game.
鲍勃  你只是个卖钢笔的  你又能怎样
Bob, you sell pens. What do you...
-噢  别啊  是他们  -谁
- Oh, no. That's them. - Who?
把我丢进垃圾桶的未来蛇头
The future felons who put me in the trash can.
嘿  蠢蛋  我们因为你被留堂了
Hey, geek-boy, we got detention because of you.
-因为你  -你要为此付出代价
- Yeah, because of you. - You're gonna pay for that.
-绅士们  我们不想惹麻烦  -他是谁  你老妈
- Gentlemen, we don't want trouble. - Who's this? Your mom?
做梦吧  他是我的保镖  我雇了他  你们最好小心点儿
You wish. He's my bodyguard. I hired him. You better watch out.
-真的  -不是  他开玩笑呢
- That true? - No. He's joking.
-我是他们的保姆  -你又能把我们怎么样
- I'm their babysitter. - What are you gonna do?
礼貌地请你让我们过去
Ask you politely to allow us to pass.
真丢人  你为什么就不做点什么呢
How humiliating. Why didn't you do something?
干嘛告诉他们我是你的保镖
Why did you tell them I was your bodyguard?
你说对了  确实很不像
You're right. I guess it was too big a stretch.
嘿  你怎么样  我是伊恩
Hey. How you doing? I'm lan.
如果我说  你有极其美丽的身体  你会过来深情地抱着我吗
If I told you, you had a beautiful body, would you hold it against me?
-至少你不害羞  -我想用最坏的方式跟她说话
- At least you're not shy. - I wanted to talk to her in the worst way.
任务完成了
Mission accomplished.
这里来
Come here.
你真漂亮
You look so pretty.
法瑞恩  我不知道你是练体操的
Farren, I didn't know you did gymnastics.
为什么要知道  你不知道我的任何事
Why would you? You don't know anything about me.
你只知道跟吉莉安出去鬼混  对我们理都不理
You come over to hang out with Gillian, and you never even talk to us.
来  我们走
Come on, let's go.
这婆娘说到重点了
The woman's got a point.
我不知道你们派谁出去买的衣服  我只知道我想杀了他们
I don't know who you are sending out to buy my clothes, but I want them killed.
-自己去啊  -我是全美国通缉的人
- You could go yourself. - I'm the most wanted man in America.
我没办法看到百货公司的货架
I cannot exactly browse the racks of JCPenneys.
只是给我一些能融入社会的东西就好  一些很有美国风的
Just give me something that will blend in. Something extremely American.
先生  我们可以进行试验了
Sir, we are ready to run the test.
棒极了
Magnificent.
她的鞋子一定有塑料成分  细菌会吃掉所有的石油制品
She must have plastic in her shoes. It will eat any petroleum product.
我们正在改善这一点
We're working on that.
细菌呢
What happened to the bacteria?
细菌完全靠石油生存  石油没了  细菌就死了
They live as long as they feed. Once the oil is gone, they disappear.
我的名鞋也没了
Just like my Jimmy Choos.
进来
Come in.
听我说  今天
Listen, about today...
你本该为我出头的  知道吗  我必须面对这些混蛋
You could have stood up for me, you know. I have to face those guys.
那就面对他们
So face them.
除非你一辈子都想在
Unless you want to spend the rest of your life
欺辱中度过
with your head in the trash can.
谢谢你的建议  鲍勃  所有问题都解决了[反语]
Thanks for the advice, Bob. All my problems are solved.
这是你们中学的作业
They assign this in middle school?
不是  业余爱好而已
No, that's my pleasure reading.
你很有天赋
You're smart.
你有很多擅长的事  为什么要把事情搞砸呢
You have a lot going for you. Why do you make things up?
女生不会对天文学感兴趣
Girls aren't exactly impressed by astrophysics.
只要给我原材料  我就能设计  制作还有发射火箭
Given the resources, I could design, build and launch a rocket
火箭能够精确地环绕月球
that would accurately circumscribe an orbit of the moon.
但是其他男生  能够玩儿花式投篮
But other guys can, you know, throw a ball through a hoop.
我不想让你陷入麻烦
I don't want you to get in trouble.
我们来一个约定吧
I'll make you a deal.
如果从现在开始说实话
If you try to tell the truth from now on,
我不会跟你妈妈说今天的事
I won't tell your mother about today.
真的吗
Really?
伙计  这可真酷
Dude, that's almost cool.
你说像我这样卖钢笔的
You mean for a guy who sells pens?
好了  孩子们  该睡觉了
Come on, kids, time for bed.
来  多吃一口
Come on, one more spoonful.
诺拉
Nora.
这首歌是我小时候在中国学的
This one I learned it in China when I was young.
是我  我需要帮助
It's me. I need your help.
我撒了天大的慌才搞到这些东西
I had to make up one heck of a yarn to get all this stuff.
你怎么跟他们说的
What did you tell them?
我就说如果明早以前找不出武器级铀
Well, let's just say if I don't find some weapons-grade uranium by dawn,
我就有麻烦了  你要这些干什么
I'm in trouble. What do you need all this for?
帮孩子们做家庭作业
To get the kids ready for school.
呵呵  就像我妈妈在东柏林的时候  经常说的一样
Well, it's like my mom always used to say when she was stationed over in East Berlin.
她说  “当间谍容易  做父母难啊”  祝你好运
She'd say, "Spying is easy. Parenting is hard." Good luck.
好极了
Bring it on.
法瑞恩  你已经在里面呆了一个早上了  让我进去
Farren, you've been in there all morning! Let me in!
法瑞恩  让我进去
Farren, let me in.
法瑞恩  你已经在里面带了一个早上了  让我进去
Farren, you've been in there all morning! Let me in!
法瑞恩
Farren.
嘿
Hey!
该轮到我了吧
I guess it's my turn.
法瑞恩  换一条长一点的裙子
And, Farren, please put on a longer skirt.
你这是在挑衅我
This means war.
诺拉
Nora?
Nora.
跟鲍勃在一起
Stay with Bob.
走吧  诺拉
Come on, Nora.
-他在哪里  -藏起来了吧
- Where is he? - Hiding.
他可能要使花招骗我们开门
He's probably going to trick us into opening the door.
帮我把东西放下来
Help me put this away?
伊恩  你知道规定
Lan. You know the rules.
不能在楼上喝汽水
No soda upstairs.
什么  你怎么
What? How did you...
早餐好了
Breakfast is served.
哇
Wow!
诺拉  该睡觉了
Nora, time for bed.
睡觉了
Night-night.
明天还要上学  该睡觉了
It's a school night. You should be asleep.
你怎么找到我的
How'd you find me?
第六感吧
Call it a hunch.
你为什么你对妈妈直呼其名呢
Why do you call your mother Gillian instead of Mom?
她不是我妈妈
She's not my mom.
什么意思
What do you mean?
我爸爸以前结过婚
My father was married before,
我的妈妈在我小时候就死了
and my real mom died when I was little.
吉莉安是继母而已
Gillian is just my stepmother.
伊恩和诺拉是我同父异母的弟弟妹妹
And lan and Nora are just my half brother and sister.
我就像家里的怪人
I'm like the freak of the family.
他的离开一定让你很伤心
It must have hurt your feelings when he left.
他会回来看我的
He'll be back for me.
我知道他不是世界上最好的父亲
I know he's not the greatest dad in the world,
但是他爱我  会回来看我
but he loves me, and he's not going to leave me here alone.
无论如何
Anyway,
你不该爬到屋顶上来  不安全
you should not climb the roof like this. It's not safe.
别告诉我不可以呆在这里
Please don't tell me I can't come up here.
这是我唯一一个可以冷静的地方了
It's like the only place I can chill.
事实上  我是想问  能不能让我给你修一个栅栏
Actually, I was going to offer to build you a railing.
你是想讨好我  让我喜欢你是吧
Are you trying to bribe me into liking you?
我只是想要你安全
I just want you to be safe.
介不介意我跟你一起冷静
Mind if I chill with you?
没问题啊
It's a free country.
看  星星
Look at the star.
好消息  我们知道  方程式是在哪里被下载的了
Good news. We got an address.
好样儿的  叫上点儿人  把方程式拿回来
Good. Take some men. Get that download back.
塔蒂安娜
Tatiana.
要赶尽杀绝
No survivors.
嘿  老板  喜欢不
Hey, boss. You like?
不喜欢
No like?
我能给一点时尚建议吗
May I make a couple of fashion suggestions?
女人不喜欢衬衫压在里面  把头发弄乱
Women don't like the shirt tucked in. Mess up your hair.
-你懂时尚  -不  但我懂女人
- You know about fashion? - No, but I know women.
像这样穿  我在电影里看过
Wear it like this. It's cool, I saw it in a movie.
什么电影  《八爪女》  现在可不是1985年
What movie? Octopussy? This isn't 1985.
-差点儿忘了  -这是什么
- I almost forgot. - What's this?
-伊基·波普和大卫·鲍伊在上海的演唱会  -什么
- Iggy Pop and David Bowie in Shanghai. - What?
这大概是世界上最难找到的演唱会碟片了
This is only about the hardest concert to find in the world.
我保证学校里没有谁有
I guarantee no one else in the school district has it.
-你为我下载的  -别担心  我付钱了
- You downloaded this for me? - Don't worry, I paid for it.
-你知道有这个演唱会都不可能啊  怎么做到的  -简单  我就在现场
- How'd you even know about it? - Easy. I was there.
鲍勃  你太有效率了 我们提前半个小时到了
Bob, you're getting too efficient. We're half an hour early.
不用谢
You're welcome.
今天开心哦
Have a great day.
-嘿  酷啊  艾伦  -谢谢  我是伊恩
- Hey, cool look, Aaron. - Thanks. It's lan.
管他的
Whatever.
今天要愉快哦
Have a great day.
听着  昨天在屋顶说了话  不代表我们就是朋友了
Look, the talk on the roof the other night doesn't mean we're friends.
但愿不会
God forbid.
找到了  没有人在
We're here. There is nobody around.
我发现电脑了  但是数据被下载到移动盘了
I found the computer, but the file was downloaded to an external storage device.
我找不到
I can't find that.
我想我知道谁住在这里了
I think I just figured out who lives here.
中央情报员鲍勃
Agent Ho.
-喂  -你不能再随便爆东西了  安东沙
- Hello. - You must stop shooting things, Antosha.
我说过  中央情报局  或者中国人拿到就糟了
I said it would be bad if the CIA or Chinese had it.
但他两个都是  找到他  但是要活的
But he's both. Find him, but keep him alive.
我需要知道他还把这个给谁看了
I need to know who else he's shown this to.
听着  现在  所有人
Listen up. Now. Everyone in here.
我们必须盯住中央情报员鲍勃
We must locate Chinese Intelligence agent, Bob Ho.
他很狡猾  是最出色的特工  而且神出鬼没
He is very tricky. The best at what he does. He won't be easy to find.
-克里尔小姐  -等会儿
- Ms. Creel. - Not now.
想象你是个训练有素的中国人  又想消失
Imagine you are Chinese, highly trained, and you want to disappear.
我看到他挽着一条挂满骷髅的绳子在爬
I see him climbing with a bunch of skulls on a rope.
他不是野蛮人  但这样想也不错
Okay, he's not Conan the Barbarian. Good try, though.
不是  是我看到他了  在那里
No, I see him. There.
上  上
Go. Go!
先别杀他  我们还需要他的情报
Don't kill him yet. We need information.
加油鲍勃  加油鲍勃 加油鲍勃  加油鲍勃  加油鲍勃
Go, Bob, go! Go, Bob, go! Go, Bob, go!
过来  小甜心  回来
Come here, sweetheart. Get back here.
过来
Come here!
放手
Let go!
-搞定这个坏女人  鲍勃  -放手
- Get the bad lady, Bob. - Let go!
-能帮我拿好乌龟吗  -一会儿再说
- Can you hold my turtle? - Not now.
耶  鲍勃
Yay, Bob!
就这样
That's it.
你要付出代价
You will pay for that,
-美国小公主  -救命  鲍勃
- little American princess. - Bob, help!
还要  还要  还要
Again, again, again.
好
Okay.
-你为什么让我们离开学校  -谁在乎  我们出来了
- Why did you pull us out of school? - Who cares? We're out.
那你怎么在前座呢  今天该我
Why are you in the front seat anyway? It's my day.
-不是  该我  -不是  不该你  你撒谎
- No, it isn't. It's my day. - No, it's not your day. You're the liar.
-不是  今天该我  -不是  今天该我
- No, today is my day. - No, today is my day.
-你撒谎  -没有没有没有
- You're a liar. - No. No. No.
-好了  安静  -我还是很饿
- All right, quiet! - I'm still hungry.
看起来这里没有嫩鸡吃
It doesn't look like they have chicken tenders here.
里面等我  我要打一个电话
Wait inside. I have to make a call.
-我是菲尔弗莱  -我是鲍勃  我需要帮助
- This is Firefly. - This is Bob Ho. I need help.
我在大学拿到了很好的成绩
Yeah, so I get pretty good grades at this university.
是优等生  我不想吹嘘  但是  你知道的
I'm top of the class. I don't like to brag, but, you know.
-鲍勃  这是拉瑞  -先生  很高兴见到你
- Bob, this is Larry. - Pleased to meet you, sir.
-我们去吃东西吧  -拉瑞上大学了
- Let's get some food. - He goes to the university.
他是个诗人  是不是很酷
He's a poet. Isn't it cool?
好极了  帅呆了  酷毙了  衰死了
It's rad. It's awesome. It's jiggy for shizzy. It's the bomb.
-进去  -嘿
- Let's go. - Hey!
真尴尬
How embarrassing.
要知道  很多人第一次见到我都不喜欢我
You know, most people don't like me when they first meet me.
但是拉瑞不是
But Larry did.
我有两个词要说  拉瑞  杯具
I have two words for you, Larry. Thirteen.
我要尿尿
I have to go.
好  诺拉  我们走  你们俩就呆在这里
All right, Nora. Come on. You two stay at the table.
不不不
No, no, no.
我不能进去
I can't go in there.
男孩们真脏
Boys are pigs.
小心
Careful.
然后狮子跳到我头上  我赤手空拳干掉了它
And the lion jumped on me, and I killed him with my bare hands,
救了上校妻子的性命
and I saved the colonel's life.
-你好勇敢  -谢谢
- You're brave. - Thanks.
这个如何呢  鲍勃  整个店的服务生都让拉瑞坐这里
How about this, Bob? The whole restaurant and the waitress sat Larry here.
-不是很棒吗  -像是命中注定
- Isn't it great? - It's like it's fate or something.
是啊  先生  我们只是闲聊一下
Really, sir, we're just goofing around.
-嘿  诺拉  当当当  -是谁敲门
- Hey, Nora. Knock, knock. - Who's there?
-爱尔兰炖肉  -什么爱尔兰炖肉
- Irish stew. - Irish stew who?
如假包换的爱尔兰炖肉
Irish stew in the name of the law.
拉瑞在跟我说在大学里的事  听起来棒极了
Larry was telling me all about the university. It sounds great.
-很高兴什么时候带你转一圈  -不可能
- I'd be glad to give you a tour sometime. - When pigs fly.
这不由你决定  你又不是我爸
It's not up to you. You're not my dad.
我不是  但是我知道  你妈妈也不会失去神智让你去
No, but I know that your mother hasn't completely lost her mind.
鲍勃  只是转一下
It's just a tour, Bob.
又不是在约会
It's not like he's asking me out on a date or anything.
是吗
Are you?
不是  只是一个友善的邀请
No, it's just a friendly offer.
即使是约会  你也不能拦我
Even if it was a date, you still couldn't stop me.
-你的专业是什么  拉瑞  -英国文学
- What's your major, Larry? - English Lit.
把酱油递给我好吗
Would you pass the soy sauce?
学习文学经典让我受益匪浅
That way I get a background in the classics.
-你说俄语  是吧  -怎么了
- You speak Russian, Larry? - What's going on?
-这会很痛  -你说得对极了
- This is going to be painful. - You're right about that.
走  走  走
Go, go, go.
或许你该就这件事写一首诗
Maybe you'll write a poem about this.
再见了  拉瑞
Goodbye, Larry.
还是算了  对我来说他太老了
Fine. He's too old for me.
鲍勃  我不想当公主了  我想当电子人
Bob, I don't want to be a princess anymore. I want to be a cyborg.
他怎么这么快找到我们的  这说不通啊
How did he find us so fast? It doesn't make sense.
-鲍勃  发生什么事了  -安静  让我想一想
- Bob, what's going on? - Please quiet, I'm trying to think.
什么意思  你说你要想一想
What do you mean, you're trying to think?
-你刚刚把一个人扔到窗外去了  -他是谁  他怎么
- You just threw a man out the window... - Who is he? What is...
好了好了  够了
All right, all right, fine. Fine.
我是个国际间谍  被中国情报局派到美国中央情报局
I am international spy, on loan to the CIA from the Chinese Intelligence Service.
有人想置我于死地  拉瑞是俄国探员  清楚了吧
Someone wants me dead, and "Larry" was a Russian operative, okay?
好了  别说了
Fine. Don't tell us.
酷
Cool.
他为什么一个人来
Why would he come alone?
呆在这里
Stay here.
-孩子们呢  -里面
- Where are the kids? - Inside.
只要孩子安全  其他的没有什么
Nothing else matters until these kids are safe. Nothing.
是啊  卡尔顿应你的要求  给孩子们建了安全屋
Of course. Colton set up that safe house for them like you requested.
-嘿  文件带了吗  -什么文件
- Hey, got that file on you? - What file?
波尔达克电脑上的  卡尔顿发给了你  你下载过
The one Colton linked you to, from Poldark's computer, your download.
我没有下载  打都没打开过
I didn't download it. I never even got it open.
别跟我绕弯弯  鲍勃  那可是绝密文件  我需要所有的拷贝
Don't BS me, Bob. It's classified material. I need all copies.
为什么说是我下载的呢
Why would you think I downloaded it?
除非有人告诉你了
Unless someone told you I had, someone who wanted it back.
别让事情麻烦了
Let's not make this thing harder than it has to be, Bob.
给我
Give me the file.
你可是国家公务人员  怎么能做这种事
You're a career officer. Why do this?
我想退出  跟你一样  我们都是为了爱
I want out. Same as you. We're both leaving for love.
只不过我爱钱  而波尔达克能给我钱  文件
Only I love money and Anton Poldark is match. Com. The file.
等一下  等等
Wait. Take it easy.
好样儿的
Good work.
哦
No.
我只能说  你是目前  我妈找过的最酷的男朋友
Can I just say, you are by far the coolest guy my mom has ever dated.
至少我知道了  拉瑞怎么这么快发现我们的了
At least now I know how that kid Larry found us so fast.
-怎么  -手表
- How? - The watch.
格雷兹让我留着手表  这一定是个跟踪系统
Glaze told me to keep the watch. It must have a tracking device.
-哇  你真的是个特工  -吉莉安绝对要疯掉
- Wow. You really are a spy. - Gillian is totally going to freak.
这是干什么
What are you doing?
石头里有铁矿  能屏蔽信号  表给我
There's iron in these rocks. It will hide the signal. Watch, please.
把今天的事告诉学校的任何一个人
You realize if I told anyone at school this story,
都会因为撒谎被留堂一年
I'd get detention for a year for lying.
-嗯  -嘿  兄弟  你在干嘛
- Yes. - Hey, partner. Where're you at?
-想干嘛  -我想要发给你的那个文件
- Why do you ask? - I needed to pick up that file I sent you.
你知道的  我想让你帮我破解的那个
You know, the one I wanted you to open for me.
鲍勃  你在吗
Bob, you there?
卡尔顿  我从来没有想过你会背叛我们  投向卡尔波特
Colton, I never thought you would have sold out to Poldark.
嘿  这什么想法  有些事不太对头  我们该聚一下讨论讨论
Hey, that's crazy, man. Something's wrong. We need to get together and talk.
-休想  -鲍勃  鲍勃
- Nice try. - Bob? Bob?
-在宾馆  我们会很安全  -这就是你的计划是吧  把我们丢在宾馆
- We'll be safe here. I promise. - This is your plan? Hide out in a hotel?
这儿也不像是有嫩鸡
Doesn't look like they have chicken tenders here, either.
好棒  我们能定房间服务吗
This is awesome. Can we order room service?
-你疯了吗  我要回家  -不行
- Are you crazy? I'm going home. - No.
-这是你们跟我在一起唯一安全的地方  -跟你一起安全
- The only place you're safe is with me. - Safe with you?
-每个人都想杀了你  -我知道  这很酷
- Everybody's trying to kill you. - I know. Isn't it cool?
嘿  鲍勃  如果你想跟我妈妈结婚  我给你写请帖
Hey, Bob, if you want to marry my mom, I'll personally write the invitations.
爱你  鲍勃
Love you, Bob.
现实点儿  鲍勃
Be realistic, Bob.
-喂  -嗨  吉莉安
- Hello. - Hi, Gillian.
嗨  小甜心
Hi, sweetheart.
外公刚刚睡着了  我正要跟你们打电话呢
Yeah, Grandpa just fell asleep. I was gonna call you guys.
我必须跟你说个事儿
I have to tell you something.
我知道这会伤害你  但是我还是要说
I know this is going to hurt you, but I have to tell you.
-你还好吧  -我没事
- Are you all right? - I'm fine.
-关于鲍勃  -他怎么了
- It's about Bob. - What about him?
他不是你想象的那样  他是个特工  中国特工
He's not who you think he is. He's a spy, a Chinese spy.
现在恐怖分子想干掉他
And these terrorists are trying to kill him
情报局也想找到他  他们
and now the CIA's after him, too, and they...
法瑞恩  我知道你不喜欢鲍勃  但是别这样啊
Farren, I know you don't like Bob, but come on.
我以为会是伊恩这样做  没想到会是你
I'd expect this from lan, but not from you.
什么  不  这是真的  他会让我们都完蛋的  你就一点儿也不在乎吗
What? No, it's true. He's going to get us all killed. Don't you even care?
法瑞恩  谈话结束了  让鲍勃接电话
Farren, this conversation is over. Put Bob on.
嗨  吉莉安
Hi, Gillian.
鲍勃  对不起  我不知道她是怎么了
Bob, I am so sorry. I don't know what's gotten into her.
-真的  -什么
- It's true. - What is?
她说的都是真的
Everything she said is all true.
不管这是什么鬼  这不搞笑
Whatever this is, it isn't funny.
孩子们很安全  我保证
The kids are safe, I promise.
你一回来我就把他们交给你
I'll give them to you as soon as you get back.
要么跟我说实话  要么我把孩子交给照看中心
You're either telling me the truth or I've left my kids with a nut job.
无论如何  你该回来接他们
Either way, you should come and get them.
那么  除了这只手表  你有其他炫的间谍用品吗
So, you got any other cool spy stuff, besides the watch?
别碰  很锋利
Don't touch. It's very sharp.
酷  还有什么
Cool. What else?
酷
Cool.
对不起  先生
Sorry, mister.
机场  快点
Airport. Step on it.
-鲍勃  你醒着的吗  -开玩笑  我怎么睡得找
- Bob? Are you awake? - Are you kidding?
-他是不是一直都这样打鼾啊  -在他房间旁你都听不到啊
- Does he always snore like that? - Can't you hear him next door?
我一直以为是猪干的
I always thought it was the pig.
你和吉莉安结束了  是吧
It's over with you and Gillian, isn't it?
是  法瑞恩  结束了
Yes, Farren, it's over.
-你赢了  -但为什么我没有赢了的感觉呢
- You win. - Then why don't I feel like I won?
如果你真的很爱她  不该这么轻易放弃
If you really loved her, you wouldn't give up this easily.
正是因为我爱她  也爱你们  所以我必须走开
It's because I love her and the three of you that I have to walk away.
你们的安全才是重要的
It's more important that you're safe.
我以为我可以让我过去的生活过去  可我不能
I thought I could put my other life behind me, but I can't.
高兴点儿  没加入这个家庭你很幸运
Be glad. You're lucky you're not joining this family.
你不知道生活在一个不该你存在的地方  是件多么痛苦的事情
You've no idea what it's like to live in a place where you totally don't belong.
别这么肯定嘛  我是一个孤儿
Don't be so sure. I was an orphan.
我在一个有很多孩子的家庭长大  从来没接触父母  但我有家
I was raised in a group home. I never knew my parents, but I had a family.
我有很多很多兄弟姐妹
I had dozens of brothers and sisters there.
我跟他们中的任何一个人都没有血缘关系  但我爱他们所有人
And I wasn't related to any of them, but I loved them all.
家不是说你跟谁有血缘
Family isn't whose blood you carry.
而是说你爱的人和爱你的人
It's who you love and who loves you.
-吉莉安  -妈妈
- Gillian! - Mom!
吉莉安  我真的很抱歉
Gillian, I'm really sorry about everything.
跟我说实话  你是不是真的是特工
Tell me the truth. Are you really a spy?
是的  我本来想在吃饭的时候跟你说的  但你打断我了
Yes, I am. I was going to tell you at dinner, but you stopped me.
我不管什么原因  你让我的孩子们危险了
I don't care. You put my children in danger.
走
Just go.
鲍勃  你什么时候回来看我呢
Bob, when are we going to see you again?
你不能来看他们
You're not.
别走  你走了谁给我唱中文歌呢
Please don't go away. Who's gonna sing me China songs?
-你们会安全  我保证  -离我的孩子远一点
- You'll be safe. I promise. - Stay away from my children.
亲爱的妈妈  我很抱歉  但我不能呆在这里
Dear Mom, I am very sorry, but I cannot stay here.
我注定要当一个特工  像鲍勃一样
My destiny is to be a spy, like Bob.
我要跟他在一起  给你最好的祝福  妈妈
I am going with him. Best wishes, your son, lan.
鲍勃的信号重新动起来了  我收到了
Ho's signal just popped back up. We got him.
开动
Let's roll.
鲍勃  鲍勃
Bob! Bob!
-伊恩  -你落下了手表
- Lan. - You left your watch.
你在这里干嘛  走啊
What are you doing here? Let's go.
什么意思  我们才刚刚到这里啊
What do you mean? We just got here.
鲍勃  真巧啊  把他们绑起来
Bob Ho. What a coincidence. Tie them up.
-你在这里干什么  伊恩  -我在找你
- What are you doing here, lan? - I'm coming with you.
我也想当特工
I want to be a spy, too.
这就是那个坏家伙啊  穿得可真够没品
Is this the bad guy? I thought he'd be better dressed.
-你怎么找到我的  -我找到了一个你的追踪设备
- How did you find me? - I found one of your tracking devices
就在拥抱你的时候放到了你的口袋里
and put it in your pocket when I hugged you goodbye.
-印象深刻  -谢谢
- I'm impressed. - Thanks.
-现在可以切入正题了吗  -我要不要强调一下我退休了
- Can we go back to business? - Would it help to mention I'm retired?
退休的人不会下载秘密
Retired men don't download secrets.
-我从来就没有下载过什么破秘密  -说谎
- I never downloaded anything. - He's lying.
你到底是要相信谁  我还是这种背叛者
Who are you going to believe? Me or the traitor?
有人很顽皮啊
Someone has been a very naughty boy.
到处放满了照相机和麦克风
He's got cameras and microphones mounted all over the place.
不错嘛  把我们引到这里来
Good plan, filming us together.
-你怎么能背叛国家呢  -很简单
- How could you turn against your country? - It's simple.
因为我会成为亿万富翁
I'm gonna be a billionaire.
记得你下载的文件吧  那是一种生物细菌的方程式
That file that you didn't download? It's a formula for a Growth Bacteria Hybrid.
那家伙专门吃石油  你可以想象
This stuff literally eats oil. Can you imagine?
一夜之间世界上
Overnight, all the world's oil supplies go poof.
除了俄国都严重缺油  这是不是很无价呢
All except for Russia's. It'll be priceless, right, comrade?
你怎么能让卡尔特跟你一起  干这事儿的呢
How did you get Colt to go along with you?
卡尔特  那个乡巴佬才不是  这个计划中的一部分呢
Colt? That hillbilly's not part of this.
他根本不知道发生了什么
He doesn't know what goes on in the real world.
还觉得格斗才是来真的呢
He still thinks wrestling is real.
让小孩走吧  他跟这场纷争没有关系
Let the boy go. He has nothing to do with this.
有人刚才闲聊已经透露了我们的全部计划
Mr. Chit-Chat just laid out our whole plan.
我们不可能放他走
We cannot let him go.
-他会走漏风声的  -相信我  没有人会相信他的
- He will tell. - Trust me, no one would believe him.
这倒是说到点子上了
He's right about that.
嘿  老板  我在外面发现了一个鬼鬼祟祟的人
Hey, boss. Look at what I found sneaking around outside.
-法瑞恩  -大家好
- Farren? - Hi, everybody.
坐啊
Please, have a seat.
别啊
This can't be happening.
波尔达克  让孩子们走  我帮你找到GBH文件
Poldark, let the children go and I will find this GBH file for you.
GBH  斯德哥尔摩GBH
GBH? Like, Stockholm GBH?
-你怎么知道  -天呐  不可能
- How do you know that? - No freaking way.
你是说这一切只是因为  他下载了一个非法的音乐会
You're telling me all of this is because he downloaded a bootleg concert?
你干的
You did what?
你下载了
You downloaded it?
哇  这个公司对秘密也忒他妈看重了吧
Wow, these companies take piracy way too seriously.
你在我电脑上乱搞  这是隐私啊
You were messing with my computer? That's private.
我只是想装酷一下
I just wanted to seem cool.
你不用装  你本来就很酷
You don't need to. You are cool.
-你是我见过的最酷的孩子之一  -谢谢
- You're one of the coolest kids I know. - Really? Thanks.
嘿  你们忽视一个带着枪的男人
Hey, over here. Man with a gun.
等等  我是你认识的唯一的孩子啊
Wait a minute. I am one of the only kids you know.
-文件在哪里  -我的iPod里  我家的桌子上
- Where is the file? - It's on my iPod, on my desk at home.
看见了吧  如果想要成为一个特工  就不能对坏蛋说实话
Now, see, you want to be a spy. Never tell the truth to the bad guy.
抱歉  我是菜鸟
Sorry, I'm new at this.
塔蒂安娜  带些人去他家  找到文件
Tatiana, take some men to the kid's house and find the iPod.
家里有人怎么办
What if the family is home?
上了这条船就要  杀了他们
Ever since you dyed your hair blonde... Kill them.
-不  别  -去  给我搞回iPod
- No, don't! - Go, bring me that iPod.
来  走  走
Come on, go. Go.
现在  你嘛
Now, as for you...
棒极了
Awesome!
法瑞恩  走
Farren, let's go.
-我找无线位图  -那我打开无线广播
- I call dibs on the front. - Then I pick the radio station.
好了  准备好了吗
Okay. Ready?
好  等等
Okay, hold on.
-喂  -吉莉安  等等
- Hello? - Gillian, listen to me.
拜拜  鲍勃
Goodbye, Bob.
吉莉安  等等  别挂
Gillian, wait. Don't hang up.
等等  我们必须在他们之前赶到
Hang on. We've got to get there before they do.
情报局里有你还可以相信的人吗  可以打电话的
Is there anyone at the agency you can still trust? Someone you can call?
当然  但是他们拿走了我的摄像头  我没有证据
Sure, but they tore out my cameras. I have no proof of anything.
不一定啊  就在刚才  我用手机录下了谈话全过程
Except that, as it happens, I recorded that entire conversation on my cell phone.
好样儿的嘛  家伙
Way to go, dork.
卡尔特  只需要听着  我有样东西要放给你听
Colt... Just listen. I'm going to play you something.
记得你下载的文件吧  那是一种生物细菌的方程式
That file that you didn't download? It's a formula for a Growth Bacteria Hybrid.
那家伙专吃石油
This stuff literally eats oil.
这是什么情况
What is this?
-今天万圣节  -今天万圣节
- It's Halloween. - It's Halloween.
-万圣节快乐  -鲍勃
- Happy Halloween. - Bob!
你们俩在干什么  我以为你们都在楼上
What are you all doing? I thought you were upstairs.
-所有人都进去  -鲍勃  我们得谈谈
- Everybody inside. - Bob, we need to talk.
妈  这不是在开玩笑  他怎么说我们就怎么做
Mom, this isn't a joke. Do whatever he says.
-好  -来
- Okay. - Come on.
-去拿你的iPod  -他的iPod
- Get your iPod. - His iPod?
-我需要一个解释  -他们来了
- I demand an explanation. - They're coming.
-谁来了  -俄国人
- Who? - The Russians.
俄国人
Russians?
我看到他们了  他们来了
I saw them outside. They're coming.
-俄国人  -是  吉莉安  俄国人
- Russians? - Yes, Gillian, Russians.
你试着跟上大家的思路吧
Let's try and keep up.
太晚了  每个人都到楼上去  明白吗
It's too late. Everybody upstairs. Understand me?
呆在这里
Stay there.
我的设备呢
Where's my stuff?
-嘿  带上一点这些东西  -这是什么
- Here, take some of this stuff. - What is all this?
保护我们的设备
Protection.
你怎么玩儿打火机呢  我不让你玩儿火
Why do you have a lighter? I don't want you playing with fire.
好吧  就这一次  走
Okay, maybe just this once. Let's go.
不请吃就捣乱
Trick or treat.
快点  关门  关门  好了
Hurry. Close it. Close it quick. Okay.
-我的乌龟不见了  -诺拉  诺拉
- I forgot Chuckle. - Nora! Nora!
你扮的是什么
What are you supposed to be?
电子人  从外星来  把你轰走
A cyborg, sent from the future to blast you away.
妈咪  那个人会飞
Mommy, that man can fly.
真不敢相信你居然这么对我们  置孩子的安危于不顾
I can't believe you did this to my family, endangered my kids.
我不是有意的  我爱他们
I didn't mean to. I love your kids.
我想跟你结婚  想跟你们四个在一起
I want to marry you, all four of you.
我也确实想过要跟你结婚
And I wanted to marry you.
但是这个美梦已经飞了
But our wedding gifts would have to be opened by the bomb squad.
好了  鲍勃  别闹了
All right, Ho. Enough games.
我以为我终于找到一个正常的男人了  一个看起来
I finally found a normal guy, I thought, someone who likes to...
我们能待会儿讨论吗
Can we talk about this later?
-他调了包  -拿下他
- He switched belts. - Get him.
把iPod给我  孩子
Give me the iPod, kid.
-我们去这个白痴家里捣捣乱  -好  捣乱
- Come on, let's TP the little geek's house. - Yeah, TP.
嘿  兄弟伙
Hey, guys.
我要走了
Gotta go.
我们要偷抢糖果  或许该从更小的小孩子身上下手
Maybe we should just stick to stealing candy from little kids.
是啊  真正的小孩
Yeah, real little kids.
-这将会很有趣  -嘿  拉瑞  咚咚
- This is going to be fun. - Hey, Larry. Knock, knock.
帅
Yes!
来  进来  关上门  快点  关门
Come on, guys, get in the room and lock the door. Hurry. Lock it.
如假包换的爱尔兰炖肉
Irish stew in the name of the law.
很抱歉你的退休时光这么快就结束了  鲍勃
Sorry your retirement was so short, Bob.
-你可以杀了我  但是请放了这一家人  -不可能  他们知道太多了
- You can kill me. Let the family go. - I can't. They've seen too much.
但是我会让你先行一步  就不会看到了
But I'll let you go first so you don't have to watch.
嘿  先生
Hey, mister.
别以为这样改变了什么
Don't think this changes anything.
-不要动  -没事
- Everybody freeze! - It's okay.
他们是好人
They're the good guys.
你这个肮脏的家伙啊  走
You stinking lowlife. Come on. Let's go.
妈妈
Mom!
嘿  把这些东西松掉
Hey, loosen these things up.
对不起  怎么了  手铐太紧了
I'm sorry. What's wrong? Got the handcuffs too tight?
我可不知道怎么松  我不过是个乡巴佬而已
I don't know how these things work. I'm just a dumb hillbilly.
-都好吗  -浑身青一块紫一块
- Everybody okay? - Bumps and bruises.
伊恩  这是真的好人
Lan, this really is the good guy.
嘿  你这是什么  孩子
Hey, what you got there, son?
兄弟伙儿  你录下对话  真不错啊
Nice work recording that conversation, partner.
你有一天能够成为一个优秀的间谍
This young man might make a heck of a spy someday.
你们要多快才会给我橙色的连衣裤
How quickly can you give me orange jumpsuit?
我怀疑过你  很抱歉
I'm sorry I suspected you.
别担心  老伙计
Don't worry about it, old buddy.
就当是语言障碍好了
Chalk it up to the language barrier.
谢谢
Thank you.
给你们带来这么多麻烦  我很抱歉
I'm sorry I put you through all this.
拜拜  吉莉安
Goodbye, Gillian.
拜拜  孩子们
Goodbye, kids.
鲍勃
Bob.
我会想你的
I'm gonna miss you.
我也一样
I'll miss you, too.
等等
Wait.
我知道他撒谎了  但是他这么做也是为了保护我们
I know he lied, but he did it to protect us.
整个过程  他唯一想做的就是保护我们  妈妈
This whole time, all he ever wanted to do was protect us, Mom.
妈妈
And, Mom,
你永远都不会找到  像鲍勃这么棒的人了  不会了
you're never gonna find a man as good as Bob, never again.
永远
Never.
我从来没想过我会说这些
I never thought I'd say this,
我同意法瑞恩说的
but I agree with Farren.
你也说点什么吧
I suppose you have something to say, too.
我想要鲍勃当我的爹地
I want Bob to be my daddy.
吉莉安  你是否愿意  让鲍勃成为你的法定丈夫呢
Do you, Gillian, take Bob to be your lawfully wedded husband?
我愿意
I do.
鲍勃  你是否愿意  让吉莉安成为你的法定妻子呢
And do you, Bob, take Gillian to be your lawfully wedded wife?
吉莉安
Gillian.
我还要告诉你一件事情
There's one more thing I have to tell you.
我的真名不是鲍勃
My name really isn't Bob.
没关系
That's okay.
我愿意
I do.
我宣布你们成为夫妻  你可以吻你的新娘了
I now pronounce you man and wife. You may kiss the bride.
准备  开拍
Ready. And action.
卡
And cut.
是啊  那个家伙太狡猾了  他能够吃下钉子拉出
No, that man's so crooked, he could eat nails and...
或许他只是想免费让他的邮箱装满油
Maybe he just wanted to fill up his gas tanks for free.
我不能责怪他
I can't blame him.
不是  那个家伙太狡猾了  他能够吃下钉子拉出
No, that man's so crooked, he could eat nails and...
对不起
Sorry.
对不起  先生
Sorry, mister.
好了
All right.
怎么了
What's going on?
鲍勃  我不想扮公主了
Bob, I don't want to be a princess anymore.
我想扮
I want to be a...
我是一个国际特工  被中国的中央情报
I'm an international spy, on loan to the CIA from the Chinese...
中央情报局
From the Chinese intelligent... Intelligent?
-情报  -情报
- Intelligence. - Intelligence.
好了  我马上收拾东西到房子那里去
Well, I'll just pick a few things and move to the house.
-卡  -这台词什么意思
- Okay, cut. - What does it mean?
我是个国际特工  被中国的中央情报
I am international spy, on loan to the CIA from the Chinese intelligent...
-什么  -情报
- What? - Intelligent.
大反派我都搞定了  三
I've brought down dictators. How tough to say...
-额  -呵呵
- Yeah. - Yes?
或许你该针对这件事写一首诗
Maybe you'll write a poem about...
诗  诗
A poem about... A poem.
或许你该针对这件事写一首诗
Maybe you'll write a poem...
或许你该  我讨厌英语
Maybe write... I hate English.
如果一个人娶了你  就是娶了你们四个
If a man marries you, he marries all four of you.
别忘了还有一只猪  一只猫和一只火鸡
Don't forget the pig, the cat and the turkey.
火鸡
And the turkey.
-火鸡  哪里来的火鸡  -不知道
- Turkey? Where's the turkey come from? - I don't know.
-是啊  我奶奶的  对不起  -卡
- Yeah, well, my grandmother's... Sorry. - Okay, cut.
奶奶很厉害  他
Grandmother's great. He plays...
卡
Let's cut.
他们忘词我就高兴
When they forget a dialogue, it makes me happy.
好样的  出来出来  摄影机需要你啊
Good work. Come out. Camera needs you.
出来
Come on.
我们在干嘛
What are we doing?
我们在干嘛  我们在拍摄  我们在拍电影
What are you doing? We're filming. We're making a movie.
有意思啊  有意思
Funny man. Funny man.
摄像机准备
A camera mark.